[Music]
hello welcome everybody and welcome to
the recording studios in Copenhagen my
name is Kurt and today we're going to
talk about the BC Talent programs and
more particularly we're going to zoom in
on the res skill program so if you have
some challenges with growing your team
or you really achieve your business
growth Ambitions because you lack people
then the next 10 minutes might be very
interesting for you because we're going
to zoom in what this program can bring
for you we're going to explain some of
the basics we're going to share some
numbers and of course we're also going
to listen to some of our partner
reactions on uh the program but before
we get started maybe what we should do
is look into a little bit more into um
why we're doing this and basically what
the the problem statement actually is we
constantly hear stories from our part
Partners um that the customers or
prospects are calling them up and
basically asking for an implementation
but the partner simply can't serve the
customer and ask the customer to wait
for another 6 months and of course that
doesn't really help anybody because the
customer might go somewhere else to your
competitors and of course I think that
all of you agree that we really need to
grow our ecosystem we need really need
to have a much more diverse ecosystem
and diversity and actually in all kinds
of aspects think about gender think
about age think about ethnicity social
backgrounds Etc but we also need to have
many more people into our ecosystem that
have industry experience or we really
need that younger generation that can
bring in these AI capabilities or these
co-pilot capabilities that your
customers are going to be wanting very
very soon before we get going and
explaining the res skill program let's
talk a little bit more about what you
can expect from the BC Talent programs
our mission is that we really are going
to build that next generation of BC
Talent professionals together we really
want to build the next generation of BC
talent and I'm pretty sure that if we
started to do a brainstorm exercise to
see like which initiatives that we could
come up with that we could basically
think about a couple but we've decided
to start on a few and the very first one
is the res skill program and the res
skill program is all about bringing
people in from outside of our current
partner ecosystem think about
um end users accountants supply chain
experts net developers working for
customers and basically we're going to
take these people and we're going to Res
skill them to become business Central
professionals so that's the first
initiative the res skill and that's the
one which is in market for uh one year
at this moment in time the second one is
our cross skill program and in our cross
skill program what basically doing over
here is that is look at people that
already are experienced in selling and
implementing business
applications um but they just don't have
the business Central experience or
product knowledge So within the cross
skill program we are going to retrain
them to become business Central
experts and then our last initiative
which is new which is the one that we're
still working on um so we really love to
engage with you on it is our upskill
program and that's all about people that
have just left uh an academic
institution they've really fresh in
their career and they're basically
stepping into our ecosystem and at the
start of their career and basically what
we're going to do for them is we're
going to um serve them also with product
knowledge with skills professional
skills but we will also give them some
absolute basics in the business like
accountancy Basics supply chain Basics
or development Basics if that is what is
needed so these are the three
initiatives that we have resk skill
cross skill and up skill today we're
going to zoom in a little bit more about
our res skill
program the program consists out of four
pillars and of course a talent program
starts with finding people and as you
can see on the slides um the recruitment
is a little bit isolated because that is
because this is an optional service in
the program right we do have partners
that have their own recruitment teams or
have a great relationship with a
recruiter and that's fine but if you're
using our recruitment Services what you
can expect from us is that we're going
to look based upon your terms what that
means is we're going to look at your
location we're going to look at the
industry needs that are important for
you going look at hard skills soft
skills make sure that they fit into your
company culture and you can also uh bet
that we are going to look into places
that you might not be looking for at
this moment in time and the best thing
about all of this it is actually
completely risk-free it means it's a no
q and no pay program if we can't find
the people then basically you don't have
to pay anything right but again optional
component only if you need it the actual
program actually start
the moment that your new hire steps into
your front door on day
one so from a training perspective we
offer content for both the product and
we will help your new highest on
professional skills training but let's
first zoom in on product training we
offer two choices there the first one is
a very modern way of learning and the
second one is a more the traditional
classroom training let's zoom in first
on the modern way of learning over here
what you get is a
case-based um
learning platform where you can learn at
your own pace wherever you are um it
will make sure that will you will go be
able to go through some specific
scenarios we'll have to learn read some
documents see some videos but if you get
stuck you can basically call up a
teacher and they will help you progress
in your knowledge the classroom training
is of course a more traditional virtual
classroom training where you come in on
a Monday morning and you basically go
through a course um if that's what you
needed for both the options that we have
have we do have the content available
for business Central completely for
developers and Consultants but we also
have content available for Power
Platform and of course we're going to
make sure that your people will get to
their certification if that is
needed next up what we're going to offer
is the professional skills training as
we talked about and let's agree upon the
fact that all of us in this industry are
primarily change agents and change
agents of course need to be representing
customer U but they also need to
represent you as uh as a partner they
need to have a learned all mentality and
not a no ad all mentality so that
basically means we really need to help
them to create that customer engaging
mindset where they can really do good
requirement Gathering do great um
effective communication do have great
pre-sale skills uh good project
methodology skills etc etc so what we're
offering is a 10 days Workshop it's half
days over 10 days um and in there we're
going to really do a virtual
implementation meet that difficult
customer do some requirements Gathering
do effective Communications U and you
can basically come in and play the
customer it's a very engaging way of
learning and we hear from our partners
that this is really the differentiator
into the program Partners really
appreciate the Prof professional skills
training and that's why we've decided to
double down on professional skills
training and you'll see me uh or hear me
talking a little bit more about
professional skills training later on
next to training we do also provide
individual coaching and that coaching
starts the moment the new hire took
their decision to join your company so
even before the first working day what
we start doing is we're going to create
an individual plan for all of your new
hires whether they are a developer or
whether they are a finance consulter or
a specialist in manufacturing we will
build an individual plan with all kinds
of Milestones um and deliverables that
the new high will have to go through
that individual plan holds components of
when is it uh that they need to do which
training from both a product perspective
and from a skills perspective but also
how fast can we integrate them into your
business activities because of course we
want to get your new hires buildable as
soon as possible the moment the plan is
finalized what we're going to do is
we're going to follow up with you and
the new hire on a weekly basis
individually and in small groups and
we're going to talk about potential Hur
potential challenges but also we will
celebrate the wins together and if
there's feedback then we will address
the feedback and if necessary we will
also make sure that that feedback has
basically been um um brought back to you
if that is if that is necessary but the
coaching element is really to manage
that retention and to really make sure
that the new hire is really happy within
uh his new
career the last element of the program
is about Community we are going to
welcome all of the new high in a global
new hire community and in that Community
they really have a safe space where they
can ask questions where they can meet
Aller people like-minded people that are
going to a very similar journey and what
we're going to do is we're going to make
sure that on a continuous basis they're
going to get um options to learn new
stuff from a product perspective and
from a skills perspective so uh what you
can expect is best practice sessions
from MVPs Microsoft who delivers content
like for example everything which is new
on co-pilot and um of course we're also
going to continuously focus on
professional skills so for example at
this moment in time we've planned a
negotiation uh work stream with a lawyer
somebody that does nothing else is
provide negotiation work streams and
we've got many more content like that
we're even going to meet uh within the
uh the development center in Copenhagen
at the end of our fiscal year to really
bring some of these people together so
the community really brings people
together and gives them an an a platform
to continuously learn so these are the
four um components that we have in the
program we start Recruitment and then
we're going to train them based on
product and on skills we will
individually coach them and then lastly
we're going to welcome them into uh a
community now what really a design PRP
principle for us into the program is
that since we can do everything at scale
it will really lower the cost for you in
uh effect fact um we really hear from
our partners that they feel that the
value for what we're delivering is
really great compared to the price that
needs to be paid and of course our role
as Microsoft is to constantly listen to
your feedback and ensure that all of you
are happy in this we are not financially
involved into the program but we um
really care about that you really like
this program because we will bring
together the best in the industry to
ensure that we have the best talent
program out there for you that's the
reason while we're doing this
program all right now let's look to some
numbers we uh just came back from
directions in Mia where we did celebrate
the program being live for one year uh
and we did have a great celebration
party uh on the program uh but also Mike
Morton our uh VP basically shared some
interesting statistics on keynot Day 2
he did share that the program currently
has 168 partner contracts uh into the
program and that is something that we're
really proud of 168 part that really are
Bridging the talent Gap with us together
in each of those contracts we do see
that pars engage in batches with of
three to five individuals so that is
something that's we would also recommend
as a best practice you can do the
program with one individual but 3 to
five is basically doing them in batches
of three to five individuals is
basically a best practice since you're
doing them in small B uh uh batches what
we've also seen is that almost one out
of three Partners although we're only
live for one year already came back to
us and told us that the program was
great that the new highest were driving
and that they really want to re-engage
the the program service so one out of
three Partners already came back um so
that's something that we're really uh
happy about next number that we want to
talk about is return on investment
because of course you want to get your
people billable as soon as as possible
so we did survey our partners and what
we did see is that people uh that going
through the program are bable within
approximately 10 to uh 12 weeks
Something That We're super happy about
of course is because of our combination
of product and professional skills that
individual coaching and inviting them
into a really Global Community we see
that our attention rate is above 95%
something that was super happy about and
which is above the industry average and
then lastly every time a partner engages
we do have a diversity conversation with
them and we're super happy to share that
at this moment time from all of our new
highs that we've recruited that
39% of females uh of new Highs are
females something that we're really
really happy about I wanted to zoom in
on one very specific case uh and that is
from which is from triangle and we
talked to kame the CEO of a triangle and
we asked her like hey can you do some
calculations on what the program really
delivered for you and she did give us a
couple of really great uh um uh figures
and facts that I want to share with you
the very first one of course the program
has a cost but she told us that the
program saved 80% of the time of the
seniors in the first three months that
the new hire was there and of course
your seniors you want to make sure that
they focus on customer activities
instead of spending time with uh the
junior so that is a really important
number the next thing she shared with us
is that the new hirs were already
buildable after 6 weeks which is of
course um a really great achievement
uh of uh what we did with them and then
lastly she also described that um if you
look to the typical job description that
the new hires that came in that they
basically lived up to that job
description within 9 months which
typically took her two years before the
program so really proud of her we do
have a really great video about um uh
triangle being in our program and I
would encourage you to check it out um
on YouTube and we will put the video
link into the description over
here so that was a small recap of uh
what we're doing with res skill um if
you want to learn more if you want to
engage with us I would basically
recommend you to go to our website which
is aka. BC Talent on that website you
will find um presentations
documentations we've got detailed
curriculum information you see all kinds
of cases of um partners that are in the
program from all over the world and this
is also the place for for you to reach
out to us we're really Keen to talk to
you to see how we can basically help
your talent Gees thank you for being
here and really look forward to engaging
with you very very soon